Guide to the Cave Canem Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Programs, 1996-2011; Series II; 8; (8 boxes)
  - Legacy conversations
    - Tracie Morris and Amiri Baraka, undated (Box 7)
    - Harryette Mullen and Lorenzo Thomas, 2005 (Box 7)
    - Black Renaissance, 2003 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 2001-2005 (Box 7)
    - Elizabeth Alexander and Rita Dove, 2003 (Box 7)
    - Toi Derricotte's questions, 2001 (Box 7)
    - E. Ethelbert Miller interviewed by Elizabeth Alexander, 2009 (Box 7)
    - Video: Walcott and Alexander, transcription, 2005 (Box 7)
    - Sonia Sanchez and Lucille Clifton, undated (Box 7)
    - MIchael Harper and Afaa Weaver, 2003; 2 (Box 7)
  - Soul Mountain Retreat & Cave Canem at Hill-Stead Museum's Sunken Garden Poetry & Music Festival, Farmington, CT, 2009 (Box 8)
  - Facing Pages, 2008 (Box 8)
  - 10th anniversary media partnership/ sponsor list- prospective, undate (Box 8)
  - Soul Mountain Retreat, 2007 (Box 8)
  - Vermont Studio Center, 2007 (Box 8)
  - Viriginia Center for Creative Arts, 2008-2010 (Box 8)
  - New York City workshops, 2008 Fall (Box 8)
  - New York City workshops, evaluations, 2008 Spring (Box 8)
  - "Waking the Ancestors," Patricia Smith, New York City workshop, 2007 March-May (Box 8)
  - New Jersey workshop I, 2006 (Box 8)
  - Pocantico Residence Program, 2008-2011 (Box 8)
  - Program summary chronology, 2007-2008 (Box 8)
  - Association of Writers & Writing Programs Annual Conference & Bookfair
    - Information books, 2008-2011; 5 (Box 8)
    - Name tags and lanyards, 2011 (Box 8)
    - Tote bags, 2011-2012; 2 (Box 8)
  - Retreats
    - Publicity brochure, 1997 (Box 8)
    - Evaluations, 1997 (Box 8)
    - Schedule of Events, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Contact lists, fellows, board members, and faculty, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Annual report, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Workshop retreat masters, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Scholarships, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Participant packets, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Evaluation results, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Applicants, yes and wait list, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Applicants, no's, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Registrations, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Scholarships, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Faculty, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Faculty contracts, signed, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Guests, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Faculty contracts, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Faculty correspondence, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Travel packet, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Letters to participants, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Schedule, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Participant correspondence and packet, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Faculty evaluations, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Evaluations, 1999 (Box 8)
    - Evaluation form, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Harryette's Handouts, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Evaluations, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Guest poets, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Fellows list, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Faculty, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Fellow registration form, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence between Michelle Elliott & Terrance Hayes, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Summer retreat maps & correspondence, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Attendees, profiles, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Expenses, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Scholarships, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Annual report, 2000; 2 (Box 9)
    - Packet for fellows, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Working schedule, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Scholarships, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence to applicants/fellows, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Information, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence for 2001, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Waitlist and foundations, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Faculty contracts, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Information, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Cranbrook correspondence, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Information, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Evaluations, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Registration, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Cranbrook rental agreement, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Lenard D. Moore Correspondence, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Cranbrook correspondence, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Income and expense, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Faculty biographies, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Annual report, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Schedule and expenses, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Scholarships, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Cranbrook letter of support, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Cranbrook site, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Food, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Cranbrook correspondence, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Budget and annual report, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Schedule, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Cranbrook contract, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Cranbrook bill and letters, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Welcome packet, 2002 (Box 9)
    - InsideOut, 2001-2002 (Box 9)
    - Waitlist, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Faculty, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Report, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Profile summary, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Schedule, 2003 (Box 9)
    - University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Packet, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Letter to fellows, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Accepted, rejected, and waitlisted fellows, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Faculty and directors correspondence, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Comparison of sites, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Contracts, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Participants choice, 2003 (Box 9)
    - University of Pittsburgh correspondence, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Letter to fellows with 5+ years, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Pittsburgh press/media addresses, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Photograph permission, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Library, 2003 (Box 9)
    - University of Pittsburg at Greensburg contract, 2003 (Box 9)
    - University of Pittsburgh correspondence, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Site needs, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Faculty, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Scholarships, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Report, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Expense report, 2004 (Box 9)
    - University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg billing and correspondence, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Staff contract and letters, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Pamphlets, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Pittsburgh/Greensburg travel information, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence to fellows, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Public relations, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Mentor/Mentee list, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Letter to returning fellows, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Accepted, rejected, and waitlisted fellows, 2004 (Box 9)
    - Juneteenth Prods., 2005 (Box 10)
    - Information, 2006 (Box 10)
    - Fellow evaluations, 2007 (Box 10)
    - Photograph and printed material, 2008 (Box 10)
    - Applications, 2008 (Box 10)
    - Evaluations, 2008 (Box 10)
    - Applications, 2009 (Box 10)
    - Photographs and printed material, 2009 (Box 10)
    - Photographs and correspondence, 2010 (Box 10)
    - Promotional material, 2010 (Box 10)
    - Evaluations and printed material, 2011 (Box 10)
    - Applications, 2010; 5 (Box 10)
    - Applications, 2010; 3 (Box 11)
    - Applications, 2011; 11 (Box 11)
    - Applications, 2012; 14 (Box 12)
    - Alison Meyer's datebooks, 2006-2008; 3 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence
    - Micklem email, 1999-2000 (Box 13)
    - Board members, 1998, undated (Box 13)
    - Chigaco- Guild, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Conference call, undated (Box 13)
    - Brochure, drafts and final print version, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Planning committee call, 2005 August (Box 13)
    - Latino poets, outreach, 2005 (Box 13)
    - Latino Writer's Conference, undated (Box 13)
    - Newsletter graphics example, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Newsletter opportunity requests, 1997 (Box 13)
    - Funder research, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Grant and research files, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Notes from Holly Sidford (Urban Institute), 2001 (Box 13)
    - Suggestions from advisory board and others, 1997 (Box 13)
    - Carrie Nickens- "Miss Carrie" 1913-2008 (Box 13)
    - VIP contacts, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Board of directors invite letter, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Letters to individuals, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Proposal rejections, 1998-1999 (Box 13)
    - Copies of approval letters for grants, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Cornelius Eady correspondence regarding fundraising, undated (Box 13)
    - Kate Rushin- Afaa Weaver, email, 1997 (Box 13)
    - Letters to individuals, 1997 (Box 13)
    - Communication for funding strategies, notes, correspondence, and lay-outs, 2002 April (Box 13)
    - Sarah Micklem notes, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Carolyn Micklem correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 13)
    - SASE, 1998 (Box 13)
    - Malaika Adero, 1999-2000 (Box 13)
    - Micklem saved reference material, undated (Box 13)
    - Advertisements, 2001 (Box 13)
    - Promotional plan research, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 13)
    - Thank you notes and well wishes, 2007-2010 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence/ ephemera, 2008-2011 (Box 13)
    - The Virginia Foundation for the Humanities, program director correspondence, 2003 (Box 13)
    - Carolyn Micklem, 2002 (Box 13)
    - Claudia Ann Seaman Poetry Award, 2001 (Box 13)
    - Michael Harper, 2001 December (Box 13)
    - Tape correspondence, 2001 (Box 13)
    - Virginia libraries, 2001 (Box 13)
    - General Motors, 2001 (Box 13)
    - Linda Susan Jackson Archives, 2010 (Box 13)
    - Foundation research, articles, etc., 1996-1997 (Box 13)
    - Vendor information, 2000 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Unsolicited submissions, 2011 (Box 13)
    - Board search committee, 1999 (Box 13)
    - Workshop chapbooks, 2011 Spring (Box 13)
- Publishing, 1996-2011; Series III; 8; (8 boxes)
  - Poetry prize
    - Poetry prize manuscript submissions, 2009; 20 (Box 14)
    - Poetry prize manuscript submissions, 2010; 8 (Box 14)
    - Poetry prize manuscript submissions, 2010; 32 (Box 15)
    - Poetry prize manuscript submissions, 2010; 36 (Box 16)
    - Poetry prize manuscript submissions, 2010; 17 (Box 17)
    - Poetry prize manuscript submissions, 2012; 17 (Box 17)
    - Poetry prize manuscript submissions, 2012; 35 (Box 18)
    - Poetry prize manuscript submissions, 2012; 31 (Box 19)
  - Website
    - Registration, 2003 (Box 20)
    - Domain agreement, 2000-2002 (Box 20)
    - Publisher permission, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Permissions, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Register.com, 2005 (Box 20)
    - Reggie Harris, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Web hosting, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Final website rewrite, 2005 (Box 20)
  - Contract with Willow Books, 2011 (Box 20)
  - Cave Canem Anthology XII, 2008-2009 (Box 20)
  - Cave Canem Northwestern University Press Poetry Prize, 2010; 2 (Box 20)
  - Publishing contracts, 2000-2004 (Box 20)
  - University of Georgia prize contract, 2006 (Box 20)
  - Publications
    - College list, undated (Box 20)
    - University of Georgia Press: Legacy Conversations, undated (Box 20)
    - University of Pittsburgh contract, 2000-2008 (Box 20)
    - Retail sites- Massachusetts, undated (Box 20)
    - Roth Publishing, 2001-2002 (Box 20)
  - Publishing: Teaching Poetry
    - Solicitation for pedagogy materials, undated (Box 20)
    - University of Georgia proposal: teaching poetry, undated (Box 20)
    - Krista- curriculum, 2005 (Box 20)
    - Exercises, 2000 (Box 20)
    - Hughes: "The Negro Artist and the Racial Mountain", undated (Box 20)
    - Black Aesthetic, undated (Box 20)
  - Book Proposals
    - Proposal, 2006 (Box 20)
    - University of Georgia: future projects, undated (Box 20)
    - Small presses report, undated (Box 20)
    - University of Georgia Press: teaching proposal, undated (Box 20)
  - Cave Canem Poetry Prize, 2010 (Box 20)
  - Cave Canem Poetry Prize, 2009; 2 (Box 20)
  - Cave Canem Poetry Prize
    - Prize winner: Ronaldo V. Wilson, 2007 (Box 20)
    - Prize winner: Dawn Lundy Martin, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Prize winners' achievements, 2003 (Box 20)
    - The Listening, reviews, 2005 (Box 20)
    - Lions Don't Eat Us, reviews, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Masters, prize reviews, 2004 (Box 20)
    - Newark News Ledger, 2004 (Box 20)
    - Guidelines, 2004-2005 (Box 20)
    - Ronaldo V. Wilson, Narrative of the Life of the Brown Boy and the White Man, undated (Box 20)
    - Poetry Prize, 2001 (Box 20)
  - Anthology orders Yale University Library, 2002 (Box 20)
  - MCACA mailing, 2001 November (Box 20)
  - Anthology, Michigan mailing, 2001 (Box 20)
  - Anthology flyer, master, 2001 (Box 20)
  - Anthology, 2003 (Box 20)
  - Doug Kearney ideas, 2004 (Box 20)
  - Anthology for fellows, 2003 (Box 20)
  - 2004 Anthology
    - Anthology discussion, 2004-2005 (Box 20)
    - Submissions, 2004 (Box 20)
  - 5th Anthology correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 20)
  - Gathering Ground
    - Archival, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 20)
    - University of Michigan- contract, 2004-2008 (Box 20)
    - Faculty/ participants/ prize recipients, undated (Box 20)
    - Marketing form, undated (Box 20)
    - Press, 2004-2006 (Box 20)
    - Promotion, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Submissions, 2004 (Box 20)
  - Ringing Ear
    - Finney, Cave Canem, editied manusctipt, PDF: FM & Poems, undated; 1 compact disc (Box 29)
    - Contract, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Contract for the Ringing Ear, Nikki Finney, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Author's guide, undated (Box 20)
    - Nikki Finney, 2003 (Box 20)
    - Final poets list, undated (Box 20)
    - Introduction, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Marketing plan, undated (Box 20)
    - Lenard Moore, 2002-2006 (Box 20)
    - Finney interview: Lucile Clifton, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Acceptance/ rejection letters, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Southern Anthology acceptance letter, 1 3.5 inch disk (Box 29)
    - Correspondence, 2003-2006 (Box 20)
    - Permissions, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Tour, 2006 (Box 20)
    - Contents and poet labels, undated (Box 20)
    - Reviews, 2007 (Box 20)
    - Submissions, 2003 (Box 20)
    - Testimonials, 2002 (Box 20)
    - Teachers' list, undated (Box 20)
  - Printed material
    - Cave Canem Anthologies, 1996-2007; 4 (Box 21)
    - Prize winning books, 1999-2011; 6 (Box 21)
  - Articles
    - Washington City Paper: "Heirs of the Dog", 1997 (Box 21)
    - Detroit Free Press: "Desiree Cooper: Poet draws others to sip at writer well, 2000 (Box 21)
    - The Nation: "The Speed of Poetry", 2000 (Box 21)
    - American Poet: Cave Canem, 2000 (Box 21)
    - Mosaic Literary Magazine: publications on Cave Canem, 2002 (Box 21)
    - Pluck!: an article on Cave Canem, 2007 (Box 21)
    - Unsorted magazines, undated (Box 21)
- Promotional Material and Collateral Literature, 1996-2011; Series IV; 1; (1 box)
  - Past newsletters, 1998, 2005, 2006 (Box 22)
  - First promotional poster for retreat, 1996 (Box 22)
  - Summer retreat poster and brochure, 1997 (Box 22)
  - Readings, 1997 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, 1998 (Box 22)
  - Retreat, 1998 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, 1999 (Box 22)
  - Retreat, 1999 (Box 22)
  - Readings, 1999 (Box 22)
  - Poetry prize winner: Natasha Tretheway, published article, 1999 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, 2000 (Box 22)
  - Prize reading: Rita Dove/ Natasha Tretheway, 2000 (Box 22)
  - Readings, 2000 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, 2001 (Box 22)
  - Readings, 2001 (Box 22)
  - Prize reading: Major Jackson, 2001 (Box 22)
  - Retreat, 2001 (Box 22)
  - Poets & Writers article, "Cave Canem: A Haven for Black Poets" by Shayla Hawkins, 2001 (Box 22)
  - Martin Arnold New York Times article mentioning Cave Canem, 2001 (Box 22)
  - Fellow mentions, 2002 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, 2002 (Box 22)
  - Retreat, 2002 (Box 22)
  - Studio Museum, 2002 (Box 22)
  - Legacy: Jayne Cortez/ Sekou Sundiata, 2002 October 24 (Box 22)
  - Reading: Komunyakaa, 2002 (Box 22)
  - Reunion reading, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Poetry jam, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Readings, 2003 (Box 22)
  - The Michigan Chronicle article on Toi Derricotte and Cave Canem by Patrick Keating, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Pittsburgh Post: "Cave Canem carves out protected place for poets" by Bob Hoover, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Tribune-Review: "Cave Canem gives minority poets a forum" by Maryann Gogniat Eidemiller, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Pittsburg City Paper: "Verse Camp" by Dan Eldridge, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Every Wednesday: "Cave Canem readers featured at MICA" by D. C. Culbertson, 2003 (Box 22)
  - 8th anniversary celebration, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Studio museum, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Legacy: Rita Dove/ Elizabeth Alexander, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Prize reading: Tracy Smith, 2003 (Box 22)
  - Detroit Free Press: "Cooper's Town" by Desiree Cooper, undated (Box 22)
  - National Black Programming Consortium, 2004 (Box 22)
  - Program brochures, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Prize reading: Amber Flora Thomas, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Retreat, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Legacy: Derek Walcott/ Elizabeth Alexander, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Readings, 2005 (Box 22)
  - New York Amsterdam News: "Derek Walcott on the art of Poetry" by Misani, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Legacy: Amiri Baraka/ Tracie Morris, 2005 (Box 22)
  - The Black Poetic Tradition Toward the 21st Century, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Legacy: Naomi Long Madgett/ Derricotte, 2006 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, 2006 (Box 22)
  - Studio museum, 2006 (Box 22)
  - The New Mexican: Lannan Foundation reading, 2006 (Box 22)
  - Readings, 2006 (Box 22)
  - Compass: Cave Canem showcases Lucille Clifton, 2006 (Box 22)
  - Gathering ground, marketing materials phase I, 2006 (Box 22)
  - Poets & Writers: "Eady Sees Cave Canem Success" by Thomas Sawyer Ellis, 2006 (Box 22)
  - Multicultural Review: Review of Gathering Ground, 2006 (Box 22)
  - Rattle: Poetry for the 21st Century, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Prize reading, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Legacy: Charles H. Rowell/ Thomas Sayers Ellis, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Program brochures, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Legacy: Arnold Rampersad/ Derricotte, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Readings, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Ringing Ear: Black Poets Lean South, a Cave Canem anthology, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Gathering Ground, 2007 (Box 22)
  - Bridge Walk: Eady/ Derricotte honored, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Poets & Writers gala benefit dinner, 2008 (Box 22)
  - State of the Art, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Patricia Smith at Enoch Pratt, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Poets on Craft: Major Jackson/ Suji Kwock Kim, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Poetry prize reading, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Collaborations, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Legacy: Ishmael Reed/ Al Young, 2008 (Box 22)
  - New Year's greeting, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Pocantico writing residency, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Cave Canem, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Seasonal program brochures, 2008 (Box 22)
  - "Hardheaded Weather," Eady book debut, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Word for Word, Bryant Park, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Walter Mosley benefit reading Pittsburgh, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Enoch Pratt Free Library reading, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Faculty and fellow mentions, 2009 (Box 22)
  - The Rona Jaffe Foundation writers' awards, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Sunken Garden Poetry & Music Festival, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Toi Derricotte- University of Pittsburgh chancellor's distinguished public service award, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Tribute to Reginald Shepherd, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Black history month reception, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Northwestern University Poetry Prize, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Elizabeth Alexander- inaugural poet, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Poets on Craft: Myronn Hardy & Cathy Park Hong, 2009 (Box 22)
  - New year greeting, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Program brochures, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Instructors read, 2009 (Box 22)
  - New York City Workshops, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Hygienic Arts, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Terrance Hayes and Adrian Metejka, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Baltimore Book Festival, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Reginald Lewis Museum, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Bryant Park Word for Word, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Howl Festival Poetry Turn On!, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Fellow mentions and events, 2009 (Box 22)
  - Readings, 2010 (Box 22)
  - Poets promoted, 2010 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, readings, and conversations, 2010 (Box 22)
  - Ota Benga and the Pygmies, 2010 (Box 22)
  - Benefit at Pratt Institute, 2010 (Box 22)
  - Program promotion, 2010-2011 (Box 22)
  - Mentions, 2011 (Box 22)
  - Workshops, readings, and conversations, 2011 (Box 22)
  - Posters, 1998-2009 (Box 27 (Oversize))
- Photographs, 1997-2010; Series V; 4.25; (5 boxes)
  - Retreats and legacy conversations, 2004-2008; 2; 21 compact discs and 1 3.5 inch disk (Box 29)
    Digital photographs in box 29: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Unsorted prints and negatives, 1997-2010; 35 (Box 23)
  - Photographs removed from boxes labeled "Photos to scan", 1997-2002; 8 (Box 24)
  - Retreat, 2001 (Box 24)
  - Workshops, retreats, and readings, 2001- 2004; 5 (Box 24)
  - Headshots and groups, 2004; 4 (Box 24)
  - Headshots and groups, 2004; 6 (Box 25)
  - Unsorted, undated (Box 25)
  - Nuyorican Cafe reading, 1998 (Box 25)
  - Pratt Library Reading- Baltimore, 2000 (Box 25)
  - Clifton- Sanchez conversations, 2001 (Box 25)
  - Reunion- Philadelphia, 2002 (Box 25)
  - AWP- Baltimore, 2003 (Box 25)
  - Reading- Chicago, 2003 (Box 25)
  - Virginia Festival of the Book- Charlottesville, 2003 (Box 25)
  - Poetry project- New York City reading, 2003 (Box 25)
  - Unsorted photographs and negatives, 2000-2003; 2 (Box 25)
  - Fellows and faculty headshots
    - Michelle Berry visit to New York City, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Harryette Mullen (faculty), 1999 (Box 25)
    - Sonia Sanchez (faculty), 1999 (Box 25)
    - Candid shots, classrooms, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Toni Lightfoot, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Evie Shockley, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Holly Bass, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Ro-Lyan Reid (fellow), 1999 (Box 25)
    - Bakar Wilson, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Brandon Johnson, 1999 (Box 25)
    - John Frazier, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Mistinguette Smith, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Carrie Allen McCray, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Terrance Hayes and Yona Harvey, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Michael Harper (faculty), 1999 (Box 25)
    - Cornelius Eady (faculty), 1999 (Box 25)
    - Tim Seibles (faculty), 1999 (Box 25)
    - Group shots, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Outdoors under the smoking tree, 1999 (Box 26)
    - Book sales, 1999 (Box 26)
    - Nuyorican reading, 1999 (Box 26)
    - Reunion- Philadelphia, 1999 (Box 26)
    - Workshop/retreat, 1997-1998; 2 (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, 1997-1998 (Box 26)
  - Website, 2004 (Box 26)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 26)
  - Toi and Cornelius, undated (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat classroom shots, 1999 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat fellow portraits, 1999 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat faculty, 1999 (Box 26)
  - Graduating class, 2000 (Box 26)
  - Participant readings- Cranbrook, 2001 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat party, 2001 (Box 26)
  - Activities- Cranbrook and casual shots, 2001 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat graduating class, 2001 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat party, 2001 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat classrooms, workshops, 2001 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat faculty, 2001 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat group photographs, 2001 (Box 26)
  - Summer fellows head shots, 2002 (Box 26)
  - Group pictures- summer- Cranbrook ceremonies, 2002 (Box 26)
  - Summer- group formal photograph, 2002 (Box 26)
  - Summer fellows- group shots, 2002 (Box 26)
  - Workshops in action- Cranbrook, 2002 (Box 26)
  - Faculty reading- Cranbrook, 2002 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat classroom shots, 2003 (Box 26)
  - Summer informal shots, 2003 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat casual pictures- dinner room, 2003 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat last day shots, 2003 (Box 26)
  - Summer workshop/retreat formal group photographs, 2003 (Box 26)
  - Scenic Cranbrook- various years, undated (Box 26)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 26)
  - Graduation, notes to Carolyn, 2006 (Box 27 (Oversize))
  - Faculty and fellows, headshots (Box 27 (Oversize))
- Audiovisual Material, 2002-2011; Series VI; 0.42; (1 box)
  Box 28 (audio and video cassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Compact discs in Box 29: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Program audio files- Legacy Conversations, readings, 2002-2011; 2; 21 compact discs (Box 29)
  - Program audio files- Legacy Conversations, readings, 2003-2005; 2; 6 audiocassettes (Box 28)
    - Amiri Baraka, MFA, writing NSV (1 of 2), 2005 May 14; 1 (Box 28, Item barcode 39002091396888)
    - Amiri Baraka, MFA, writing NSV (2 of 2), 2005 May 14; 1 (Box 28, Item barcode 39002091396896)
    - Lorenzo Thomas / Harryette Mullen (1 of 2), copy, 2004 October 26; 1 (Box 28, Item barcode 39002091396904)